[♪ opening theme song playing]
BEYOND JOURNEY'S END
29 YEARS AFTER THE DEATH
OF HIMMEL THE HERO,
IN THE BIER REGION, LOCATED
ON THE NORTHERN PLATEAU
♪
[STARK] So, there are cities
on the Northern Plateau.
[FERN] Cities full of bars.
Across the entire region,
this is the only area
that's able to produce grain.
Hence the bars and breweries.
[STARK] Hm...
[MAN 1] Old Man Fass
was spinning quite the yarn.
Says he's almost found Boshaft.
[MAN 2] Think he means it?
He's been digging...
Am I supposed to know
what Boshaft is?
Master Heiter told me
when I was young.
Long ago, most of the continent
was ruled
by a single great empire.
Boshaft was an exquisite liquor
crafted for the emperor.
[STARK] Hmm.
Because of Mistress Frieren,
Master Heiter
never got to partake.
♪
I crushed his dream
for good reason.
[door creaks open]
I'd like to move in
and out of this city quickly.
Once we're finished shopping,
we should--
[MAN] Frieren?
As I live and breathe!
[pants]
I haven't seen you
in a century.
[FRIEREN] Just a brief
80 years, Fass.
[FASS] You're a stickler
for details now?
Time has changed you. Mmm.
And it's changed
your roster, too.
Lost the young drunkard
somewhere along the way?
The corrupt priest is dead.
Heiter went peacefully.
[Fass sighs]
[FASS] I see.
So, I was too late, then.
[FASS] I did it.
I've finally located Boshaft.
I just need a final push.
Your magic
would come in very handy.
I don't understand how my magic
has anything to do with Boshaft.
[FASS] Then let me show you.
♪
[FASS] It's in here.
[FERN] How curious.
Is this a mine?
[FASS] Dug it myself.
This mine's all mine.
Folks assume
that all of us dwarves
have mining in our blood.
But I grew up in the city.
I started my journey
from scratch.
A small price to pay
for that legendary liquor.
You want to give us
a little context
on the old guy?
That's Fass.
No one loves liquor
as much as him.
He's spent over 200 years
searching for Boshaft.
Eighty years ago,
he asked my previous party
for assistance as well,
but believe it or not,
we had a Demon King
to defeat at the time.
So we declined.
[Heiter exclaims]
My precious, Boshaft!
[HIMMEL] Let go already!
-[Heiter cries]
-[Himmel grunts]
Pulling Heiter
away from the search
was no mean feat.
[FERN]
Your mine is very impressive.
But why would
the liquor be down here?
[FASS]
According to local legend,
there's a large store of Boshaft
locked somewhere
in the underground ruins.
[FASS] And the legend is true.
I confirmed that
much two centuries ago
when I found
this stone monument.
It's written in ancient Elvish.
The inscription proclaims
"Boshaft is the finest spirit
of all time.
Milliarde."
That must be
who engraved the stone.
[FASS] You're awfully
well-educated.
I've never met a young lady
so fluent in ancient Elvish.
That's my mistress.
She drilled it into me
when I was young.
[FRIEREN]
Most grimoires are written
in ancient Elvish, Fern.
If you want to be a mage,
you'll have to learn
how to read it.
[Fern groans softly]
So, it was Milliarde after all.
[FERN] Huh?
[FASS] Ever since discovering
this inscription,
I've dedicated my long life
to finding Boshaft.
And after all these years,
it's almost within my grasp.
[FRIEREN] You found the ruins?
[FASS] Yes. Locating the store
isn't the problem.
It's these doors.
Someone put up
a powerful barrier.
I suppose they didn't want
a drunk dwarf like me
raiding their liquor cabinet.
You on the other hand...
you should be able
to break through.
[FRIEREN] I can't.
[FASS] Somehow, I doubt that.
Removing the barrier
will be a tedious task.
These kids won't appreciate
the wait.
[FASS] I'll make it
worth your while.
With a grimoire?
[FASS] With money!
I'll pay you
twenty Reich gold coins.
It's not worth considering.
[FASS] Please, Frieren!
Not only is tasting Boshaft
my dream, it's my life's work!
I've poured every day
I've had into this
for over two hundred years!
I can't.
[Fass exclaims softly]
[Fass sighs]
Mistress Frieren, would it be
so wrong to help him?
He needs a mage.
Don't you wanna make
an old man's dream come true?
Your change of heart
is disturbing.
You'd normally object
to this sort of thing.
Mistress Frieren,
he's offering 20 gold coins.
We need money.
We'll finally be able
to buy food and gear
without bleeding
our pockets dry!
[Frieren groans]
Just so you know,
this barrier will take me
three months to remove.
[FERN] That's hardly
any time at all.
[FRIEREN] What?
Glad to be on board!
[FRIEREN] Don't come
crying to me later.
♪
[FERN] We're in the final stages
of removing the barrier.
Our work here
shall be done tomorrow.
[FERN] You don't look
very pleased.
For I'm not.
Boshaft doesn't taste good.
It's dreadful.
And certainly not worth
200 years of devotion.
But the inscription praised it.
Long life comes at a cost.
Elves will do anything
to avoid being crushed
by the weight of boredom.
♪
[footsteps]
[FRIEREN]
Anytime I see you, Milliarde,
you're staring off into space.
Many of our fellow elves
tie themselves
to a grand pursuit.
Some glorious
and lifelong adventure.
Know why that is?
Go on.
So that they don't end up
like me.
Frieren...
Suppose you spent a lifetime
searching for something
only to find it was worthless...
Imagine the feeling.
I cannot.
What is it you're talking about?
Oh, nothing interesting.
Just my distant past.
This liquor is terrible.
Disgusting.
That's Boshaft, right?
They served it to everyone
at the coronation
because it's
exceptionally cheap.
[MILLIARDE]
Before coming to this village,
I carved
a mysterious inscription
into a block of stone.
It said, "Boshaft is
the finest spirit of all time."
What exactly was the point
of doing that?
[MILLIARDE]
There was no point at all.
[FASS] It's finally time.
[Fass gasps]
[Fass laughs]
[FASS] It's perfectly preserved!
I can't believe
that after all these years,
I get to taste it.
Let's have a toast.
I'm not drinking alone!
[gulping]
This is...
[HEITER] Frieren,
the Boshaft was so close,
I could taste it.
Why drag us away?
You're a connoisseur
of liquor, aren't you?
But of course I am.
How very priestly of you,
corrupt priest.
[FRIEREN]
Let's say you've found a spirit
you've searched for
your entire life.
What would you do
if it was terrible?
Uh?
Mmm. You want to know
what I would do?
I would laugh it off.
Can't drink it for the taste?
It's booze.
It's best shared with friends.
[FASS] It's so...
[FRIEREN] It's terrible.
I would go so far as to say
it's the worst drink I've had.
[both gasp]
[FRIEREN]
Don't sit back and watch.
Join in our misery, Stark.
Yeah, I think I'm good.
You said it's terrible.
[FRIEREN]
Find out for yourself.
[gags] This is disgusting.
-[coughs]
-Did you enjoy?
-I'll give it to you this time.
-Have more.
We should've left this garbage
in the ground!
[FASS]
It really is terrible.
[chuckles]
[laughs]
We've got plenty to go around.
And I'm prepared to make
the whole city suffer with me.
♪
[FASS] Frieren?
My search may have ended
in disappointment,
but I've never had
such a fun night.
I'm glad you three stuck around
for the party.
There's nothing that pairs
with bad liquor
quite like good times.
[Fass laughs]
EPISODE 33: LOGISTICS
IN THE NORTHERN PLATEAU
30 YEARS AFTER THE DEATH
OF HIMMEL THE HERO,
IN NORM COMPANY TERRITORY,
LOCATED ON THE NORTHERN PLATEAU
Here. Take your share
of today's bread.
Is this some kind of sick joke?
It clunked.
You ever hear bread clunk?
If I know anything,
it's that bread shouldn't clunk.
[FERN]
It's been a week of this,
and each day,
the bread gets more rock-like.
Complaining will
get you nowhere.
As you saw, the Bier region
has its share of grain,
but beyond that,
the Northern Plateau is barren.
And from what I can tell,
goods aren't circulating
right now.
While we're on the road,
don't expect anything
but this delightful treat.
Oh, how depressing.
[FRIEREN]
Muster your zeal, complainers.
There should be a decent meal
within a half day's walk.
♪
[STARK] That's
an impressive fortress city.
[FRIEREN]
It's the Norm Company's estate.
The structure in the center
is their headquarters.
They deal in various goods,
primarily wheat
from the Bier region.
Unlike many
smaller trading companies,
they're armed.
They have the logistical ability
and military force
to supply the villages
dotted across the plateau.
Not even the state
can touch them.
Practically speaking,
they control all human life
that graces
the Northern Plateau.
So, they supply the villages?
But earlier, you said
goods aren't circulating.
[FRIEREN] And that's a problem.
I don't know
the specific cause,
but I'm sure time
has changed things.
Perhaps the Norm Company
isn't as mighty as it once was.
Regardless, I imagine they still
have a great deal of influence
over the goings on
and daily life on the plateau.
As such, we should avoid
making waves.
♪
[RECEPTIONIST] Very good.
First-class mages
are welcome to pass.
Travel safe, Miss Fern.
Mmm.
That elf...
[FRIEREN] Mm?
[exclaims softly]
[RECEPTIONIST]
One moment please.
[FERN] I wonder what's going on.
-[door closes]
-[FRIEREN] Hm.
I am Norm,
the company president.
And I take it
you're Miss Frieren
from the party of heroes.
I'm afraid
you owe me some money.
That's eighty years of debt
to be paid in full.
Have you been carrying debt
for our entire journey
together, Mistress?
Just a little.
We're doomed, huh?
I was told eighty years ago,
I could pay it back at any time.
That is unfortunately
not what the documents say.
A verbal agreement
won't hold up.
It seems my predecessor's
predecessor
had a more relaxed approach.
But I didn't inherit
his generosity.
[NORM] That's three Strahl
and twenty Reich gold.
Various silvers
and coppers, too.
Quite the fortune
you've acquired.
You're as wealthy
as a minor noble.
I know. Your dear grandfather
did my party a great favor
back in his day. I'll let you
keep the change, sonny.
My!
I'm afraid
this isn't nearly enough.
It seems I'll be working
in the company's mines
for the next
three hundred years.
You may journey forth,
but my journey ends here.
[both exclaim softly]
[FERN] What are you
talking about, Mistress Frieren?
Did you lose your bag in there?
And your clothing?
They snapped up all my
worldly possessions
as collateral.
[footsteps]
[both gasp]
[Frieren whimpers]
[inhales and exhales angrily]
[inhales and exhales loudly]
♪
[miners grunt]
[FRIEREN] Farewell, Fern, Stark.
Lead full lives.
[STARK] Uh...
-What are we going to do now?
-[Fern sighs]
We have no choice but to
buy back Mistress Frieren.
She's not another grimoire,
you know.
A very noble pursuit,
but unfortunately,
there's nothing you can do.
See for yourself.
The interest
has really piled up on her.
She owes over
five hundred Strahl gold.
Convert it into the region's
Reich gold currency,
and Frieren still owes me
over 300 coins.
If you believe you can procure
such a sum, I'm all ears.
That would be impossible.
Plan A is out of the question.
And we don't have 300 years
to wait around.
[FRIEREN]
I thoroughly detest mines.
It's like cooking
in a dusty clay oven.
-[footsteps]
-[Frieren gasps]
[Frieren groans softly]
The president told us
all about you, Miss Frieren.
The pleasure's ours.
Indeed.
Shall we get started then?
♪
[miners gasp, grunt]
[miner exclaims, grunts]
Aim your axes
at this wall here.
You're sure about this?
If you know who I am,
you shouldn't have to ask.
Well, you heard the lady.
Start digging, boys.
[MINERS] Sir!
[all grunting]
[FRIEREN]
When I met your president
two generations ago,
he was a cast-out nobleman,
driven to the plateau
by necessity.
He invested in this barren land
and created a logistics network.
He brought stability
to the unstable,
making him a savior
to the people who call
the Northern Plateau home.
At the time, most nobles
turned up their noses
at our ragtag party of heroes.
But he provided us funds
with no repayment deadline.
I never would have guessed
his grandson would treat me
with such disrespect.
But a busy man like you
wouldn't trek down
to such depths
without good reason.
If there's something
you wish to ask, ask it.
We have lost our grip
on logistics.
You can tell that much, yes?
I suppose so.
My companions complain
they've never had
to suffer through
such rock-hard bread before.
[NORM] I believe it. I'm not
particularly fond myself.
When it rains, it pours.
And the Norm Company
is drowning.
We've lost
a third of our troops,
their lives taken and caravans
destroyed by the demons.
Our logistics network
is in ruins.
If the Norm Company
were a nation,
we would have fallen by now.
But we're not a nation.
We're a trading company.
As long as we have the funds...
we can rebuild.
When you arrived in this region,
I felt you were hand-delivered
by the Goddess herself.
What was once a scrap of paper
marked with your party's names,
became my ticket out of ruin.
This mine is rich,
but still under development.
If we strike silver,
then we will turn
a great profit.
Enough to rebuild
what the demons stole,
and enough to repay
your party's debt.
Finding silver
should be a simple task
for the legendary Frieren.
"Legendary"?
It would take
more than a scrap of paper
to bend a legend
into doing your bidding.
[NORM] If our logistics network
falls apart,
countless people will starve
and die.
Miss Frieren,
please save the people
of the Northern Plateau.
I beseech you.
What's more,
if you help us locate silver,
I'll ensure
the bread here is soft.
Otherwise, days of rocks
await you.
If nothing else,
you certainly inherited
your grandfather's shrewdness.
This is why I avoid
working with merchants.
You have a deal.
Not that you need one.
I intended to repay the debt
I owed your grandfather
at one point or another.
♪
[MINER]
I can't believe we did it.
I've never seen so much silver.
[Frieren chuckles]
I've returned.
My journey shall continue.
You nailed the timing.
We were just coming up
with a way to bust you out.
Our plan was to raid the mine
once the sun went down.
[FRIEREN]
Goodness. You're so hot-blooded.
This detour wasn't for naught.
We'll get to eat soft bread
from now on.
[STARK] Huh?
I'm a little lost here.
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[METHODE]
I was worried to death.
[STARK]
I'll help you bury them.
[CAPTAIN]
Protect the villagers!
[FRIEREN] It seems
we were one step behind.
[FERN]
There were so few of them.
[METHODE]
So, Miss Fern also received
a demon-slaying request?